preplounge.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy of PrepLounge

The protection of your privacy is an important objective for us when processing your personal data. The information further below is summarized in the next paragraphs:    
You control who can access your information.

  * We do not send e-mails with unsolicited advertisements.
  * You can simply delete your data, unsubscribe from the PrepLounge and the newsletter every time you want to.
  * We will not forward your personal data to third parties without your explicit permission.

With the following declaration, we would like to inform you in detail about the handling of your personal data. Personal data refers to all particulars of your personal or professional circumstances.   
In case you register with PrepLounge, we need some personal data before you can make full use of our services.  
We expressly ask you for your permission to process these spereately obtained data. Also in this case you may revoke your permission, that we recorded, at any time becoming effective for the future. 

  * [Use of third party services, that communicate personal data abroad](https://www.preplounge.com/en/privacypolicy.php#nutzungvon)

## § 1 Commitment of PrepLounge

The protection of your privacy is an important objective for PrepLounge. Therefore we collect, process and use the personal data, to the extent that is legally permissible under German law. In addition, we also consider the data protection rules, that are set by the European Union. 

The in the existing [terms and conditions](https://www.preplounge.com/en/conditions.php) contained regulations for the treatment of data are supplemented by this privacy policy by explaining the type, extent and purpose of the data use to the user and informing him about his rights.

We will only use your personal information to enable you the utilisation of this website. 

We also use personal information in order to send e-mails and to provide other services. We will only use the adresses to send advertising, if you have agreed to the distribution of advertising before and did not contradict later, what you can do at any time. We will point that out to you at all times.

We will not pass your data on to any third party, in particular not for advertising and marketing purposes, unless you have given your consent previously.

We use Google Analytics. Please refer to the [comments](https://www.preplounge.com/en/googleanalytics.php).

The following data will be stored: 

  * The user's IP adress
  * Use of our website 
  * Information about the browser used

These data are collected and processed by Google. We also use third party services, such as "Facebook Connect", to authenticate users. Please note that you agreed to the use of this service and the use of your personal data by registering at these third-party companies. This use is therefore based on the [terms and conditions](https://www.preplounge.com/en/conditions.php) and the privacy policy of Facebook. In this respect, these service providers, are the body designated to use your data.

We advert to you that our privacy policy does not apply to the processing of your data by third parties, because we are not the body designated to process your data. 

We ask you to be aware of the consequences of using our services – and to accept the usage, that is necessary for the registration. Other users and third parties will also draw conclusions about your person by your usage patterns and your contributions of any kind.

## § 2 Acceptance

With acceptance of this privacy policy you agree that 

PrepLounge GmbH, Venloer Str. 47-53, 50672 Köln  
will use and process your personal data der Nutzung und Verarbeitung Ihrer personenbezogenen Daten according to this statement.

You are entitled to revoke your consent at any time. Please address your retraction to: 

PrepLounge GmbH, Venloer Str. 47-53, 50672 Köln, contact@preplounge.com

If you revoke your consent Wenn Sie die Einwilligung widerrufen, we will not be able to provide our services and may have to terminate the contract with you in case of doubt. Your personal data will be definitely deleted after the termination of your membership.

## § 3 Use of the personal data

PrepLounge uses the personal data of the user profile solely for the justification, execution and processing of the contract on the platform PrepLounge. 

The use of the website of the service provider is principally possible without giving any personal details by the user. But if you want to actively participate on PrepLounge and want to access further features, a user-registration, and therefore a declaration of several personal data is required. PrepLounge will use and process the personal data for the purpose of providing a effective, safe, user-friendly and user-related service. This results in the storage and use of the data.

In no case will your personal data be forwarded to a third party for the purpose of advertising or marketing. Personal data" are all single entries about personal or factual relations of an identified or identifiable natural person.

## § 4 Necessary information for use

Depending on what you use, please provide the following information: 

4a)  Registration and use of the online video platform PrepLounge. Extending the data set with comprehensive life cycle data, that can be shown to companies after approval of the user if applicable.  

4b)  Use of services provided by third parties 

ad 4a) The registration as a member requires the storage and processing

of the following data:  
Biographical and personal information: 

  * First and Last name
  * Date of birth (day, month, year)
  * E-Mail adresse
  * Profession
  * Qualifications
  * Gender
  * Professional status
  * Academic major
  * Industry interest
  * Employer
  * University studies

Additional biographical data can be entered optionally, that affects for example your resume or your interests. 

Use:  
After registration other members of PrepLounge can see your user profile with the information you provided. The user can not determine which data is visible to other members and which remain private.

The following can be accessed:

  * Firstname
  * Date of birth (day, month, year)
  * Profession
  * Qualifications
  * Gender
  * Professional status
  * Academic major
  * Industry interest
  * Employer
  * University studies

ad 4b)  The use of services that are provided by third parties may result in a further processing of personal data. The user can use these services only by a further consent and will be advised of the data processing of the third party service at an appropriate point. An exception are certain services of Facebook (for example Facebook Connect) and Google Analytics. For this, the separate privacy policy of [Google Analytics](https://www.preplounge.com/en/googleanalytics.php) and the [Facebook services](https://www.preplounge.com/en/facebooksocialplug.php) have to be observed. 

## § 5 Logging of data by logfile

When you access our website, your browser automatically transmits data to our web server for technical reasons. These data include, among others, the date and time of access, the URL of the referring web page, the called up file, the quantity of data transmitted, the browser type and version, the operating system and the IP-adresse. This data will be separated from other data that you stored in the context of the use to enter our offer. We do not connect this information to a certain person, unless we are called upon in court. 

## § 6 Use of cookies

### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on your computer when visiting a website. This text file stores information that can be read by the website when visiting it again at a later date. Some of these cookies are necessary because otherwise the site is unable to function properly. Other cookies are convenient for the visitor: they remember your username in a secure way as well as your language preferences, for example. Cookies mean that you do not need to fill out the same information each time you visit a website.

### Why does PrepLounge use cookies?

PrepLounge uses cookies to help us provide you with a better user experience tailored to your personal preferences. By using cookies PrepLounge makes sure that you do not receive or need to enter the same information every single time you visit the PrepLounge website. Cookies are also used to optimise the performance of the website. For example, cookies make the login process easier.  
To protect your personal details as well as against any possible loss of information or any form of unlawful processing, PrepLounge has taken appropriate organisational and technical measures.

### How can I disable cookies?

You can modify your browser to turn off cookies. This is very easy to do. Please note: if you disable cookies, your user name and password will no longer be stored on any website

**Firefox:**

  1. Open Firefox.
  2. At the top of the Firefox window, click on the "Firefox" button and then select "Options".
  3. Select the "Privacy" panel.
  4. Set "Firefox will:" to "Use custom settings for history". Uncheck "Accept cookies from sites" to disable cookies. 
  5. Click "OK" to close the Options window.

**Internet Explorer:**

  1. Open Internet Explorer.
  2. Click the "Tools" button, and then click "Internet Options".
  3. Click the "Privacy" tab, and then, under "Settings" move the slider to the top to block all cookies, and then click "OK".

**Google Chrome:**

  1. Open Google Chrome.
  2. Click on the tool icon.
  3. Select Settings".
  4. Near the bottom of the page, click "Show advanced settings".
  5. In the "Privacy" section, click "Content settings".
  6. To disable cookies, select "Block sites from setting any data".

**Safari:**

  1. Open Safari.
  2. Choose "Preferences" in the toolbar and then click "Privacy" (You can find the tool bar which looks like a gearwheel, above and on the right in the Safari window.)
  3. In the "Block cookies" section, you can specify if and when Safari should accept cookies from websites To see an explanation of the options, click the Help button (question mark)
  4. If you want to see which websites store cookies on your computer, click Details.

## § 7 Use of third party services, that communicate personal data abroad

This site uses also Google Analytics and the services and features of the Internet service Facebook. In this context, special cookies will be stored. Please note that in this respect information may be a further transfered to foreign countries. The separate privacy policy of [Facebook](https://www.preplounge.com/en/facebooksocialplug.php) and [Google Analytics](https://www.preplounge.com/en/googleanalytics.php) apply for this transmissions. Please note that we do not transmit the willfully in the contact forms entered data abroad. 

## § 8 Logging

The content of this consent is logged by PrepLounge. The consent can be revoked at any time by the user. 

## § 9 Right of access

You are entitled at any time to demand information about whether and what data has been stored in its systems about your person. Please contact 

PrepLounge GmbH, Venloer Str. 47-53, 50672 Köln, contact@preplounge.com

## § 10 Access to the private policy

You can access and print out the privacy policy from every page. 

## § 11 Contact for privacy questions

Responsible for questions on data protection is Nils Riemann, whom you can contact us as given below:  

## § 12 Data protection supervision

Responsible for the data protection supervision is prior: The representative from the North Rhine-Westphalia department for data protection, P.O. Box 20 04 44, 40102 Düsseldorf, Tel.: 0211/38424-0, Fax: 0211/38424-10, E-mail: poststelle@ldi.nrw.de
